[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
So some of the rules of visual design can help take a data visualization and
有一些视觉设计的规则 是对数据可视化有帮助的
make it more appealing so that people will want to look at it and
它们可以让数据更吸引人 从而让人们更加愿意去看
investigate it more.
和更深入研究
We don't have time to go into all the rules of visual design,
我们没有时间研究 所有的视觉设计规则
but I can basically summarize a few of the rules that have come from Edward Tufte,
但我可以基本总结一些 来自Edward Tufte (爱德华·塔夫特) 的规则
who's written several books on the subject.
他在这个领域著有多部力作
The first one is to let the data speak.
第一条规则就是让数据说话
It's very easy when we're collecting data and doing our data processing.
当我们收集和处理数据的时候
To smooth our data, to try to remove outliers and
我们很容易试图清理数据 尝试去除离群的数据
try to fill in missing data gaps and so on.
以及尝试填补缺失的数据 等等
Sometimes it's best just to display the data and let human reasoning,
有时候最好直接显示 数据来让人们自己推理
the reasoning of our cognitive systems be able to take care of those details.
我们的认知系统的推理 能够处理那些细节
For example, here's life expectancy data for two countries, Belize and Bermuda.
比如说 这里有两个国家的预期寿命数据 Belize (伯利兹) 和 Bermuda (百慕大)
Belize has data for all the years from 1960 to 2012 and
伯利兹有从 1960到2012年的全部数据
Bermuda is missing a lot of data.
百慕大则缺失了很多数据
It's got a lot of gaps here until the year 2000.
直到2000年 这里都有很多空缺
And so I could have filled this in with
因此我本可以填补这些空缺
plausible data or drawn lines between these.
用一些看似合理的数据 或者是在数据点之间连线
But it's better to just let your inductive system fill these in with
不过让你的推断系统去填补
what you would expect to be between these data points.
你认为应该在 这的数据其实更好
And also to let your abductive reasoning try to figure out why the data wasn't
同时让你的演绎推理去 尝试找出为什么在这些空缺里
being gathered in these gaps.
数据没有被收集
Another design rule is that a picture's worth a thousand words.
另一个设计规则是 一图胜千言
So you can often show with a diagram or
所以你可以经常通过展示一个图表
a picture things that it would take a lot of text to describe.
或者一张图片 来传达需要用很多 文字来描述的信息
This is a very old illustration.
这是一个很老的例子
It's a visualization by Charles Minard in 1869 of Napoleon's army
是 Charles Minard （查尔斯·米纳德） 在1869 年作的视图 描述的是
as it's marching towards Moscow.
拿破仑的军队进军莫斯科的情况
And the width of this line is the size of the army.
这条线的宽度代表军队的规模
And it gets to Moscow, and
当它到达莫斯科时
it's withered down to a small size compared to what it started with.
它衰减到很小的规模 相比它开始的时候
And then it begins a retreat.
然后它开始撤退
The size of the army becomes even smaller,
军队规模变的更小
in part because of the falling temperatures which are plotted down here.
部分原因是由于骤降的温度 如图中所展示
It may take a lot of text or annotation in order to describe what the army size was.
要描述军队规模可能需要 非常多的文字备注说明
But you can see visually here, based on this pictorially,
但你可以在这里形象地看到
what's going on a lot better and in a smaller space.
发生了什么 用的空间却很小
With that said, even though you can say a lot with pictures,
同时 即使你可以 用图表达很多
you still need to say a lot with words.
你仍然需要用很多文字
Most importantly you should not forget to label your axes.
最重要的 你不应该忘记标记你的坐标轴
It's very important to label your axes.
标记你的坐标轴非常重要
Here's a couple diagrams from some of my own publications where we're plotting
这里是一些来自 我自己的出版物的图表
various data or various behaviors.
绘制是不同的数据和模式
You can see there's a lot of attention that needs to go into annotations to not
你能看到有非常多的 注意力是花在备注上面
only make sure that the reader understands what's being plotted,
这是为了保证读者不仅仅 能读懂我们在绘制什么
but also understands the semantics behind the graph.
而且能够明白图形背后的语义
What bars at this altitude versus this altitude mean?
条形图上这个高度和那个高度分别意味着什吗 ?
What this line means here versus this line here?
这条线是什么意思 那条线又是什么意思 ?
So annotation words are still important to visualization and
所以备注文字对可视化来说 还是重要的
it's the relationship between the words and
往往是几何图形与文字之间的关系
the geometry often that gets the job done in a visualization.
让一个可视化完成它的使命
You can also add too much information to a visualization.
你也有可能 在可视化中加入太多信息
Tufte's advice is encapsulated nicely in the term chart junk.
图表垃圾这个词 很好地概括了Tufte (塔夫特) 的建议
Which basically says that when you try to make a visualization look prettier and
它的意思是当你尝试往一个 可视化作品中加入很多元素
add a lot of elements to a visualization, those elements can detract from
来让它更好看的时候 那些元素可能会分散本该集中在
the actual message that the visualization is trying to provide to the observer.
可视化作品实际上想要 传达给读者的信息上的注意力
Very commonly three dimensions can make a two-dimensional graph look more engaging.
通常来说三维立体会 比二维图像更加吸引人
This three-dimensional graph looks nicer than this two dimensional graph.
这个三维图就比 二维的图更好看
But as we've seen with perspective, if I've got a bar that's farther away,
但是就像我们在中透视所看到的 如果我们有一个远处的柱体
if I have a bar in the forefront and a bar in the background,
一个近处的柱体 还有一个在背景中的柱体
sometimes it can be difficult to see if a bar in the background is shorter because
有时候会很难分辨出 那个在背景中的柱体更短
it's farther away or is it shorter because it's representing a smaller amount?
是否是因为它很远 还是因为它代表着一个更小的数量 ?
So it's better to avoid three dimensions.
所以最好要避免三维立体
And it's better to avoid adding a lot of extraneous details to a chart that
而且最好要避免添加太多无关细节到图表上
may make it look more engaging but could detract from its real message.
那样看起来虽然很吸引人 但会分散对信息本身的注意
A nice quantitative measure of chart junk is the data-ink ratio.
一个不错的衡量图表垃圾的尺度 叫做数据 - 墨水比 （或数墨比）
The data-ink ratio basically states that
数墨比代表的是
how much data are you displaying in your visualization
你的可视化中展示的数据量
divided by how much ink are you using in the visualization.
除以你的可视化中使用了多少墨水
So, you want to maximize the data-ink ratio.
所以 你需要最大化你的数墨比
Meaning, you want to display as much data as possible using as little ink
这意味着 你想要尽可能 用最少的墨水
as possible.
更多的景点尽量恢复其原貌
So for example, here's a perfectly good bar chart displaying some item
举例来说 这是一个显示了一到五个 单位的数据的柱状图
in units of one, two, three, four, and five unit gaps there.
在这五个单位间隔中
I can display the exact same thing without these horizontal lines,
我可以显示同样的内容 但是不使用这些横线
without even the annotations here on the left, because the annotations are changing
甚至也不需要左边这些 备注 因为备注是变化的
by counting numbers one, two, three, four, and five.
即从一 到 二 三 四 五
I can just display them as stacked discreet bar segments and
我可以直接把它们显示成 堆叠的简单的分段柱状图
I can see the same information that
所能看到的信息是一样的
this is basically some value a little more than four.
如这里是一个比四大一点的值
This is some value a bit larger than two.
这里是一个比二大一些的值
I can see the same information here,
我从这能读出同样的信息
I've used less ink and I can focus more on the actual data.
我使用了更少的墨水 而能更多地集中在实际数据上
This is an example where Ed Tufte reveals that he's really a minimalist.
Ed Tufte(爱德华 塔夫特) 的这个例子 表明他是一个名副其实的极简主义者
He wants as little decoration as possible in visualizations.
在可视化中他想要使用尽可能少的装饰
There are other people working in visualization who have set up
也有其他从事数据可视化的人们
different design aesthetics that have also generated effective visualizations.
制定了不同的设计美学标准 也能产生有效的可视化作品
So Tufte is not the only name in visualization and the only advice you
所以 Tufte (塔夫特) 不是在可视化领域中 唯一的名字 他的建议也非唯一
should follow, but these are good recommendations in any case.
不过这些不论在任何情况下 都是好的建议
Another principle is the micro and the macro of a visualization.
另外一个原则是 可视化中的宏观与微观
So you've got micro level details and macro level details.
有宏观层面的细节 也有微观层面的细节
The best example is, again, from the NCSA, here's another visualization of a tornado.
这里又一个来自 NCSA 的最后的例子 另一个关于龙卷风的可视化图
On the bottom here we've got wind being displayed, perhaps,
底部我们可以看到 是风被显示的样子
as little stalks of wheat.
大概是小束的麦子一样
You can see wind direction here in the foreground and
你能看到前景中显示的风向
in the background that becomes more of a texture.
背景则仅能看到纹理
So you've got micro-level and macro-level details.
所以你既有宏观细节 也有微观细节
We can create zoomable interfaces.
我们也创作可缩放的界面
Zoomable interfaces allow us to change
可缩放的界面让我们能够改变
which details are at the macro level that we can look at, and
哪些宏观细节我们想要看到
which details are at the micro level which we can get a broad overview of.
以及哪些细节应该在微观层面 有一个宽泛的概览
This leads to this mantra for
这就引导出了这句 常用的话语
doing large data visualization, where you want to see a broad overview first, and
做大数据的可视化 你先会想要 有一个大略的概览 然后
then get the details on demand, and be able to zoom into those details,
再根据要求获取细节 继而能在这些细节中放大
and be able to switch from a macro view to a micro view.
还能够在宏观和微观 两种视角中切换
It's also
这也是
to think of information as being organized into layers.
把信息分层组织起来的思想
This is a visualization project that I was a part of a few years ago, where we were
这是一个几年前我参与了的 可视化项目 我们当时正在
visualizing the structure of music in a different layout than is usual for music.
尝试用不寻常的方式 视觉化音乐的结构
So we're visualizing, for example, note values here in blue and
我们将音符用蓝色代表
we're visualizing similar chord structures in black characters.
然后我们将相似的和弦 用黑色代表
And I'm showing some relationships in light grey of neighboring elements to
然后我用浅灰色显示一些邻近元素 之间的关联
a given relationship organized in heavy black here.
以及这里一个用深黑色代表的 特定关系
So by using these different design elements, changing the color,
所以通过使用不同的设计元素 改变颜色
changing typeface, italics or bold,
改变字体 斜体或者加粗
you can organize the visual display of information a little bit better,
你可以将信息的视觉显示 归纳整理得好一些
give hints to the viewer of the different categories.
给读者不同的类别的提示
This is very similar to the display of nominal data using hue,
这类似于用色调来显示标称数据
for example, or using a different type face, or
比如说 用一个不同的字体
a different decoration as a way of discriminating between nominal variable.
或者另外一种装饰来区分不同的 标称数据
Also multiples, Tufte speaks of multiples.
还有倍数设计原则 同样Tufte （塔夫特） 也提到
That is to basically maintain a consistent design and
那就是在多个可视化中 保持一个一致的设计
have multiple visualizations using that same consistent design so
在多个可视化中使用同样的 一致的设计
that you can see the differences as the data changes.
这样你能看到数据中变化的不同
So in this example from one of my own papers we have several different graphs.
这是来自我的论文中的一个例子 其中有几个不同的图表
In each case, I've tried to maintain the exact same the same vertical axis.
在每个里面我都尝试 保留完全一样的纵坐标
The same annotation for the different cases.
不同的情况使用一样的备注
And, in fact, as much as possible, the same horizontal axis, although it
以及 尽可能地使有一样的横坐标
changes a little bit, so that you can see the difference from graph to graph
尽管它还是有一点改变 这样你能看到每个图标之间 的不同
in addition to the individual changes in the data variables inside each graph.
除了每张图表中自己 独立的数据变量变化
Visualizations, especially
在可视化方面 尤其是
presentation visualization and interactive storytelling, tell a story.
展示可视化和互动叙事 都是在表达一个故事
So you might think, what sort of story is your data visualization actually telling?
所以你可能会想你的数据可视化是在 描述一个怎样的故事呢 ?
The best way to think of this is, what's happening over time?
最好是这样来思考 就是 随着时间推移发生了什么？
What's happening across space?
随着空间的不同发生了什么？
Here is a plot of life expectancy in Rwanda and
这是一个关于卢旺达和
the neighboring Republic of Congo.
和其邻国刚果共和国的预期寿命的分布图
And you see this huge dip in the life expectancy in Rwanda.
你能看到在卢旺达的寿命预期 这里有一个很大下跌
This is just tragic and a lot's going on here.
这里发生的事情很令人悲伤
These two lines are telling quite a story because they're describing two
这两条线就讲述了一个故事 因为它们在描述两个
neighboring countries and very different circumstances in the two countries.
相邻的国家而且是两个 国家中非常不同的情形
And finally, color.
最后 颜色
Your choice of color can be important if it's used properly, but
如果运用得当 你的颜色选择是非常重要的
color chosen arbitrarily can be quite harmful.
但随意挑选的颜色 可能会非常有害
In this example, rainbow is not the best.
在这个例子中 彩虹色就不是最好的选择
As we'll see next, the choice of color could be very important and
像我们接下来要看到的 对于颜色的选择可能非常重要
there's additional design decisions to be made based on the choice of color.
基于颜色的选择 需要作出一些额外的设计决定
Here we're looking at a three-dimensional object and
这里我们在看一个三维立体的物体
we're using a rainbow map that has bright and dark spots in it.
然后我们用了有亮和暗点的 彩虹色谱在上面
Those bright and
这些明暗点
dark spots can interfere with our perception of the three-dimensional shape.
会影响我们对三维立体 形状的认知
Also the shading of the three-dimensional shape can interfere
同样它的光影也会影响
with our perception of the variable that's being mapped to color.
我们感知与变量匹配的颜色
So these rules came from Tufte's books.
这些规则都是来自Tufte （塔夫特） 的书
Tufte tends to be a minimalist.
Tufte （塔夫特） 倾向于是个极简主义者
He tends to want to use the least amount
他想要在可视化中
of presentation possible in a visualization.
用尽可能最少的视觉元素
And that's one design criterion.
而这也是一个设计准则
But it's only one of many design criterions.
但也是多种设计准则中的其中一个
I encourage you to look at other visualizations from other designers and
我鼓励你们也去看其他 设计师的可视化作品
to maybe explore your own sense of design style.
然后也许能探索出 你自己的设计风格
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community